기억이라 해도 여러 종류가 있는데,
우선 레인이 레인이라는 기억.
유전이라는 말 알지?
레인은 이런 얼굴의 이런 체형의 아이라고
그게 분자 레벨로 기록되어 있는거야.
뇌 외에도 몸의 곳곳에 어떤 흔적이 있어서 기록되어 있는거야.
그리고, 몸에 상처를 입으면 피가 나고 조금 있으면 딱지가 생기잖니?
그것도 세포 조직 내에 기록되어 있는 게 재생되는 거야.
그리고 또, 훈련하는 운동선수는 무의식적으로 몸이 먼저 움직인다고들 하잖아?
무의식적으로 몸이 먼저 움직인다고들 하잖아?
그것도 몸이 기억한다는 거야.
기록을 재생하면 기억인가요?
그렇다고 할 수도 있지만, 그렇지 않을 때도 있어.
인간은 적당주의자들이잖아?
선생님도 어릴 적 기억은 확실히 기억하지 못해.
가족끼리 즐거웠던 추억도 어쩌면 다른 사람은 즐겁지 않았을지도 몰라.
I may have had misperceptions in the moment, or I may have remembered things incorrectly and by mistake.
But we all walk around with memories, thinking that what we remember is what actually happened.
Suppose you meet an old friend that you haven’t seen in a long time.
Don’t you remember the things you used to do with that person right away?
Your memory has a way of linking things together.
If you can’t link things together, you’re sick?
Well, there is something called memory impediment.
People who have this can’t remember things that happened only moments ago.
They have no idea of how things in the past took place.
They don’t know what happened and in what order.
Since they don’t want anyone to know that they don’t remember things, they often make up stories about the past to fool people.
Humans are complex.
We do all sorts of things.
You’ve seen senile old people on TV shows, haven’t you?
As humans, there are some things we can’t do anything about.
Things we can’t do anything about?
I’m not saying that you’re sick, Lain.
There are things we can’t do anything about, aren’t there?
We can’t flap our arms and fly, can we?
There are memories in the body and the brain?
There are still many things we don’t understand.
The human brain is made up of many different things.
When something is recorded there, there is a change that takes place that becomes the foundation for memories.
모르겠어.
그렇구나.
좀 더 커서 고등학교나 대학교에 가면 공부할 수 있어.
그래도 흥미를 가진다는건 좋은 거야.
그저 레인은 병에 걸린게 아닐 테니까.
저, 제 기억이 제 것이 아닌 것 같아요.
그럴 때도 있어, 선생님도 그래.
저인데, 그거 말고는 아무것도 생각나지 않아요.
잊어버린 것 뿐이야.
말했잖니, 레인? 인간은 적당주의자들이라고?
멋대로 생각하거나 잊어버렸다고 생각해버리는 생물이야.
그게 평범한 거야.
평범?
그래. 레인은 너무 신경을 써. 평범한 건데.